（ビショップ）
パズルナンバー　Ｊ－２２Ｅ号…　解放。
Puzzle number J-22E: solved.
Ｊ－８５Ｖ号…　解放。
J-85V: solved.
Ｊ－９９Ｇ号…　解放。
J-99G: solved.
Ｊ－２０７Ｈ号…　解放。
報告は　以上になります。
J-207H: solved.
This concludes my report.
It's unbelievable, isn't it. The Sage Puzzles...
（ダイスマン）信じられないっすね。
賢者のパズルが…。
And a single guy solved four in a row.
（メイズ）立て続けに　４つも。
しかも　たった１人に。
（フンガ）√学園のソルヴァーか。
（ビショップ）そのとおりです。
A Root Academy Solver?
Exactly.
すべてのパズルを解放したのが　彼。
大門カイト　オルペウスの契約者なのです。
He was the one who solved all the puzzles.
Daimon Kaito, the contractor of Orpheus.
（ダイスマン）
こんなバカ面したやつが…。
He's making such an stupid face.
（メイズ）オルペウスの契約によって
覚醒した能力は？
What abilities did he get from the contract with Orpheus?
（ビショップ）
詳しい情報は　今のところ…。
We don't know the details as of now.
（フンガ）
だが　この者　いまだ　その力を→
But it would seem that he's not yet able to use his abilities to the fullest.
完全には使いこなせて
いないようではないか。
というより　彼自身は　契約を
拒否したがっている様子。
On the contrary, it seems he's rejecting the contract himself.
He's rejecting the power that only a chosen few can reach?
選ばれし者にしか
与えられない能力を拒否？
本物のバカではないのか？
Is he actually an idiot?
I have doubts on whether he's fit for the Armband or not.
（ダイスマン）彼が　腕輪にふさわしい
人間か　どうかっていうのが→
はなはだ疑問なんすが。
（ルーク）ならば　試してみよう。
In that case, let us test him.
彼の過去は　調べがついています。
試すのに　うってつけのパズルも。
We have records of his past. We also know the puzzle that is appropriate for testing him.
（ルーク）見定めさせてもらおう。
大門カイト。
Daimon Kaito, let us discern whether or not you are capable...
ファイ・ブレインの資格を持つ者か
どうか。
of achieving the Phi Brain.
kimi no nounai he shinnyuu nemutteiru sukima ni
I infiltrate your brain while you're sleeping.
Baby, open the gate!
fukuzatsu sugi sekyuriti kakusareru to abakitaku naru
The security's too tough, but I want to expose what's hidden.
barabara ni chirabatteiru pasuwado wo hiroi atsume
I gather the pieces of the shattered password.
kakushin ni sematte iku sono shoutai wo misete
I get close to the core. Show me who you really are!
kantan ni kuria dekinai saki nante motto yomenai
I can't clear it easily. I can't even see what lies ahead.
kaidoku fukanou sumairu kikenna pazuru
Your indecipherable smile is a hazardous puzzle.
rokku sareta doa aru nara zutto tataite miru beki kazana hiraku wa
When you see a locked door, you should just hit it until a crack opens.
eien ni hodokenai nazo nanka wa nai
There's no mystery that lasts forever!
makiokosu, it's a supernova
I made it, it's a supernova!
tobikiri shigekitekina hirameki wo agemashou
Let's flash so bright it'd hurt!
Misskey-Misskey La-Tu-Ma
yume no naka it's a supernova
In my dreams, it's a supernova!
watashi wa sou brain diver
Yeah, I'm the brain diver!
kimi ga sagashi motometeru kotae ni nareru made
Until I can find the answer you're looking for...
Brain diver!
Invitation From a Nightmare
（アイリ）天才テラス？
（武田）ああ。
Genius terrace?
Yeah. The first terrace of the cafeteria turned into a hangout for guys with titles.
食堂第一テラスが　称号を持つ
やつらのたまり場になったそうだ。
なぜ　そこまで　好き勝手させる？
Why do they get to do whatever they want?
学園長も　生徒会長も
何を考えているのだ！
What are the principal and the student council prez thinking?
They can eat as much as they want in a place reserved just for them. Sounds great!
（相沢）飯　食い放題専用スペース付き。
いいねぇ！
（アイリ）天才テラスですか！
Genius terrace, was it?
やっぱり　称号を持っている
人たちって　すてきです！
The people with titles are so awesome!
They're all weirdos.
（ノノハ）変人ばっかりなんですけど。
（キュービック）いいよ！　カイト！
いい脳波　出てるよ！
Nice, Kaito! You're giving off great brainwaves!
I'll build a lighthouse there!
（アナ）アナ　ここに　灯台建てるんだ！
好きにして。
Whatever.
（ギャモン）おっ！　ごちそうさま！
ごぉち…　ん　ぐ～っ！
Thanks for the meal!
Thanks for th-
ネギで　てこずった！
俺の勝ちだな。
The onions got me!
I won.
てめえじゃねえ！　ネギだ。
ネギに負けたんだよ！
Not you, the onions! I lost to the onions!
Just accept your defeat like a man!
んだと？！　見苦しいやつだ。
ネギに礼を言うんだな。
Thank the onions!
They're all weirdos, but they sure are good at puzzles.
変人ばっかりだけど
パズルだけは　すごいのよね。
カイト！　家庭科で作ったクッキー。
ノノハスイーツ。
Hey, Kaito! I made some cookies in home ec!
Nonoha sweets!
（ギャモン・キュービック）ノノハスイーツ？！
近づくな！　危ねえぞ！
Nonoha sweets?
Watch out! It's dangerous!
何それ？！　失礼ね。
お前　忘れたのかよ！
What do you mean? That's rude!
Did you forget the last time?
回想
（カイトの泣き声）
（ノノハ）いた。
There you are.
（カイト）ウン…　ノノハ…。
Nonoha...
はい。　カイトのために作ったの。
食べて　元気出して。
Here, I made these for you.
Have some and cheer up.
ありがとう。
Thanks.
んんんん？！
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
カイト？　ちょっと？
おいしかった？
Kaito? Hey!
Was it good?
ねえ　おいしかったんでしょう？
カイト！　カイト！
It was good, right?
Kaito! Kaito!
ちょっと　カイト！
Hey, Kaito!
That was a really close call.
あの時は　マジで危なかった。
照れちゃって　もう。　あまりの
おいしさに泣きやんだくせに。
You're making me blush! It was so good you stopped crying!
んなわけ　あるか！
フン　女の手料理なんて興味ねえが→
Like hell it was!
I don't really care about women's cooking,
しかたねぇ　俺が味見してやるか。
キューちゃん　味見。
but I don't have a choice, so I'll give them a try.
Cubie, have a taste.
あっ　聞いてねぇ。
キュービック・Ｇ！　ちゃんと呼んでよね。
She's not listening.
My name is Cubic Galois! Call me that!
See, they're good right?
ねぇ！　おいしいでしょう。
うん　悪くはないね　ノノハ。
Yeah, they're not bad, Nonoha.
なんで　上から目線？！
Why are you looking down on me?
I see you're all getting along well.
（ソウジ）仲よく　やってるねぇ！
軸川先輩！
Jikugawa!
ダビンチ　ガリレオ　エジソン　そして　アインシュタイン。
Da Vinci, Galileo, Edison and Einstein.
称号を持つ天才同士
これからも協力して→
I hope you geniuses will work together to solve more puzzles in the future!
パズルに挑んでもらいたいね。
冗談だろ。
You're kidding, right?. I have no intention of putting up with them.
俺は　こいつらと
つるむつもりはねぇ。
え～っ？！
じゃあ　なんで　毎日
ここにいるの？
Then why are you here every day?
ホントは　結構　気に入って
いるんじゃないの？　みんなの事。
You've actually come to like them, haven't you?
ちげ～よ。
ここは見晴らしがいいから…。
Yeah right! It just has a great view.
あっ？！　何　あれ？
What's that?
The POG?!
ＰＯＧ？！
（ビショップ）大門カイト様ですね？
You are Daimon Kaito?
ＰＯＧジャパン　中央戦略室付きギヴァー
ビショップと申します。
I am Bishop, a Giver from the Japanese Strategic Center of the POG.
お迎えにあがりました。
オルペウスの契約者である　あなたを。
I came here for you, the contractor of Orpheus.
我々は　あなたの能力を
大変高く　評価しております。
We place great value in your abilities.
今後のために　一度お会いし
さまざまな疑問にもお答えしたい。
For the sake of our future cooperation,
the head of POG Japan wishes to meet with you
それが　ＰＯＧジャパン
総責任者の考えです。
and answer any questions you might have.
また　学園長が
何か仕組んでるのか？
Is the principal planning something again?
いや…　さすがに
今回は　ありえない。
No, he's got nothing to do with this.
いかが　なさいますか？
やめた方がいいよ。　何か危険だよ。
Your decision?
You shouldn't. It looks dangerous.
Do not worry. We are not barbarians who hurt people.
ご安心を。
我々は　人を傷つけるような→
野蛮な組織ではありませんので。
Outside of puzzles, that is.
パズル以外では…　だろ。
分かった。　行くぜ。
カイト？！
Okay, I'm going.
Kaito!
人殺しのクソパズルを作って
いい気になってるやつらに→
There's a lot of stuff I want to say to the guys
言いてえ事が山ほどあるしな。
じゃあ　私も行きます！
who make those fucking murderous puzzles!
Then, I'm going too!
俺もだ。
なんで？！
Me too!
Why?
その総責任者ってやつに
話があんだよ。
I have stuff to say to that leader guy too.
賢者のパズルを解いてほしいなら
俺に言えってな！
Like to call me if they want a Sage Puzzle solved!
では　ご学友の方々も　どうぞ。
In that case, your friends may accompany you.
I'm not going. I hate flying machines.
僕　行かないよ。　飛行機　嫌いだし。
アナも。　絵　描きかけだし。
Me neither. I'm in the middle of drawing.
どこまで行くんだろうね。
おい　ＰＯＧのおっさん。
How far are we going?
Hey, dude from the POG!
（ビショップ）はい。
オルペウスの契約者って何なんだ？
Yes?
What's that Orpheus contract thing you were talking about?
オルペウスの腕輪に　選ばれた者の
ことですよ。
腕輪？！
It means being chosen by the Armband of Orpheus.
Armband?
（ビショップ）オルペウスの腕輪は
人間の脳を極限まで活性化し→
It is said that the Armband of Orpheus allows people to use their brain to its fullest,
眠っている能力を覚醒させると
言われているのです。
awakening their hidden abilities.
ただし　それが　どんな能力かは
人によって違いますが。
However, what those abilities are, depends on the person.
Is it really that amazing?
そんなに　すごいものだったの？！
（ギャモン）じゃあ　こいつ→
So you can only solve puzzles because of the Armband? Disgusting!
腕輪のおかげで　パズルが
解けてたって事かよ。　だっせえ！
いえいえ　パズルの才能がない者を
腕輪は選びません。
No, no. The Armband only chooses people who have talent for solving puzzles.
「賢者のパズル」に挑む力が
あるからこそ→
The POG had recognized Daimon Kaito as a top-grade solver
capable of challenging Sage Puzzles before.
我々ＰＯＧも　大門カイト様を　当代一の
ソルヴァーとして認めたのです。
だから　カイトにばっかり　パズルが…。
Is that why he's getting all the puzzles?
ケッ！　何で　こんな
ネギも食えねえやつが。
And he can't even eat onions.
ネギ　関係ねえ！
もう　ケンカしないの！
Onions have nothing to do with this!
Stop fighting!
（バロン）まさか　ＰＯＧが
直接　学園に…。
I didn't expect the POG to come here personally.
やはり　ご存じなかったのですか？
So you knew nothing about it?
ＰＯＧの動きを　すべて
つかむなど　不可能だ。
I can't even hope to understand all the POG's actions.
私は　一介の学園長に
すぎませんから。
I'm just an ordinary academy principal.
万一　彼らに何かあったら…。
What if something happens to them?
If they can't overcome the obstacles, then it only confirms their abilities.
乗り越えられなければ
その程度だったということです。
（キュービック）ふん　実験は成功。
Experiment complete!
The Kaito Surveillance Micromachine. It works long distance as well.
カイト観察用マイクロマシン　遠距離でも
間違いなく機能している。
逃がさないよ。
You're not getting away.
（ギャモン）着いたみたいだな。
Looks like we're here.
This is the laboratory of POG Japan.
（ビショップ）ここが　我がＰＯＧジャパンの
研究所です。
おっきい～！
It's huge!
The history of Sage Puzzles is the history of battles between Givers and Solvers.
賢者のパズルの歴史とは
ギヴァーとソルヴァーの戦いの歴史。
ここには　過去に作られた
パズルの情報が集められ→
Here, we gather information on past puzzles
日々　新たなパズルが
生み出されているのです。
and create new ones every day.
あっ　あれ見て！
えっ？！
Look at that!
Puzzle of God?
パズル・オブ・ゴッド？！
「神のパズル」だと？！
そういう意味だったんだ！
The Divine Puzzle?
So that's what it meant!
Welcome to the POG.
（ルーク）ようこそ　ＰＯＧへ。
What a huge underground building!
地下に　こんな施設が…。
You must be tired from the long trip.
長旅　お疲れさまでした。
この先に　おもてなしのパズルを
３つ　ご用意しましたので→
To help you relax, we've prepared three puzzles for you.
Please challenge them.
ご堪能いただければ　幸いです。
（ビショップ）「総責任者は　この先で
皆様をお待ちしております。→
The Head is waiting for you ahead.
では　ご健闘を」。
Have a nice fight.
（ギャモン）お偉いさんには　タダでは
会わせねえってことか。
So we can't just meet Mr. Elite Guy? They're annoying.
ケチくせえぜ！
こいつが　１つ目のパズルか。
ディスクタワーだな。
This is the first puzzle? Looks like a normal disc tower.
パズルタイムの始まりだ。
It's puzzle time.
ディスクタワーって。
ディスクを回転させて→
Disc tower? What's that?
You rotate the discs so that the columns don't have any matching colors.
縦に同じ色が来ないように
全部の列をそろえんだよ。
このパズルは　俺が解くぜ！
I'll solve this puzzle. I have to impress Mr. Elite Guy.
偉いさんに　アピールしなきゃ
いけねえんでな。
俺様の実力ってやつを。
I'll show him my true powers.
その腕輪　くっつく相手を
間違えたってな。
And that it's a mistake to go with this armband freak.
好きにしろよ。　このパズル　向こうで
飽きるほど　やったからな。
Do what you want. I got bored of this puzzle back there.
向こうだぁ？
カイト　イギリスに留学してたの。
Back there?
Kaito studied abroad in England once.
クロスフィールド学院ってとこ。
あっ！　クロ…！
At the Crossfield academy.
Wha-?! The Cro-?!
天才ばっか育ててるっつう
あの名門か？！
That famous academy that only takes geniuses?!
こんなバカが　そんな所に？
学園長が勝手に決めたんだよ。
What was an idiot like you doing there?
The principal decided it on his own.
あ～？！　学園長が　育ての親？！
He's your guardian?!
I didn't know you had that kind of a relationship!
てめえらが
そんな関係だったとはな。
それで
特別扱いしてもらってんのか。
That's why you get all the special treatment?
As if. Instead, he's always causing trouble for me.
ねえよ。　むしろ　こっちは
迷惑してるっての！
もう　そんなこと言わない。
Don't say that! He saved you when you were all alone!
独りぼっちのカイトを
助けてくれた恩人でしょう！
独り？　あっ！
（回転する音）
Alone?
あっ！　うわ～！
ノノハ！
Nonoha!
ありがとう。
Thanks.
うっ！　いや！　う～　痛たっ！
気をつけろよ！　…ったく。
And... Ouch!
Watch it, seriously.
ああ　ごめん　ごめん。
Sorry, sorry.
It opened.
あっ　開いた！
こういうことか。
So that was it?
これで　次へ。
On to the next one!
回想
（ルーク）これ　ディスクタワーっていうの？
This one's called a disc tower?
ストーンヘンジ！
A Stonehenge?
What kind of a puzzle is this?
今度は　どんなパズルなの？
You just need to adjust the height of all the stones.
（ギャモン）石の高さを　全部そろえりゃ
いいのさ。
カイト　どうしたの？
えっ？！　あっ　ああ…。
Kaito, what is it?
何だ！　こいつも　向こうで
やったってやつか？
ああ。
You telling me you did this over there as well?
Yeah.
Well then, just sit back and watch as I solve this puzzle!
だったら　俺様が華麗に…。
どうなってるんだ？
カイト？
What's going on?
Kaito?
見てねえし。
He's not even listening.
I told you to watch out!
だから　気をつけろって！
だって　急に！
But it happened too fast!
Hey, let's go!
オラ！　行くぞ！
何　怒ってんだ？
What are you mad about?
別に怒ってねえし。
I'm not mad at all!
心の声
ハノイの塔…　ポリキューブ…　タングラム。
Tower of Hanoi... Polycube... Tangram...
心の声
全部…　俺が
昔　好きだったパズルばかり。
These are all puzzles that I loved!
偶然か…　それとも
心の声
わざと　このルートを。
Is it a coincidence? Or is this route intentionally...
心の声
このルートを選んだのは　誰だ？
Who chose this route?
What does he know about me?
心の声
俺の何を知っている？
着いたぜ。　最後のパズルだ。
We're here, this is the last puzzle.
次　お前　いっぺん　やってみるか？
You wanna try solving the next one?
No, thanks.
いや　いい。
そうか…。
Oh, okay...
心の声
何があるんだ？　この先に。
What's waiting for us ahead?
うそ？！…　だろ。
You're kidding me.
What kind of a puzzle is this?
どういうパズルなんだ？　こいつは。
メモっとくね　一応。
Let's take notes anyway.
光る３つの四角。　こいつは何だ？
２つのもあるわよ。
Three bright rectangles. What is this?
There's two of them.
（２人）うわっ！
動くんだ。
It moves!
こりゃあ　落ちたら　やべえぞ！
マジ　気をつけろよ！
If you fall here, it's all over! Be careful!
えっ？！　落ちた！
んで　１個　光が消える。
It fell!
And one light goes off.
あっ！　４つ消えたよ。
なるほど。
Four went out over there!
I see.
あそこに　ゴールしたとき
光を全部　消してりゃ→
So that door will only open if every light is out by the time we get there?
あのドアが開くってことか。
そうなの？
Really?
Probably.
たぶんな。
たぶんって。
Probably?!
Just shut up and come with me, Nonoha!
いいから　黙って俺についてこい！
ノノハ！
プレートの動き方は
あみだくじと同じだ。
The plates move the same way as in a ghost leg.
A ghost leg?
あみだくじ？　おお　ホントだ。
Oh, they really do!
移動した先にあるプレートは
光の数に関わりなく→
The plate at the destination will go out and fall regardless of the number of lights it has on.
全部消えて　落っこちる。
で　乗ってた方の光は　１つ消える。
And one light goes off on the one we're standing on.
よし！　間違いねえ。
Okay, now I'm sure!
心の声
どうして？
どうして　このパズルが　ここに？
Why?
Why is this puzzle here?!
次は　こっちだ。
This way next!
これで　また４つ　消えたね。
次は　向こうだ！
Now four more went out.
That one next!
あっ　ちょっと　そんなに強く
引っ張らなくても　ついてくから。
You don't have to hold so tightly, I'm keeping up!
ああっ！　別に　俺は
そんな強く手を握ったりとか→
I-It's not like I want to hold on to you tightly or anything!
そんな事したいわけじゃ。
はぁっ！
っていうか　ずいぶん何回も
行ったり来たりするのね。
We're going around a lot by the way.
ただ　消しゃあ　いいってもんじゃ
ねえからな。
Because it's not only about making them go out.
全てのプレートを落とし　全ての光を
消して　ゴールにたどりつくには→
We have to drop all the plates, make all the lights go out, and arrive at the goal.
このルートしか　ねえんだよな。
さすが　天才！
This route's the only way.
You are really a genius!
ナッ　ハハハ！
もっと褒めても　いいんだぜ。
Please praise me more if you'd like!
ああ！　ほら　こっちだ。
あっ　うっ。
Come on, this way!
父さん…　母さん。
回想
Dad... Mom...
これって…　これって！
回想
This... This...
It's a puzzle!
パズルだ！
回想
（ロープが切れる音）
If only I'd... If only I'd realized sooner that it was a puzzle...
僕が…　もっと早く…　もっと早く
パズルだって　分かっていれば。
ゲッ…。
ダメかと思った。
That was too close.
こんな仕掛け　俺様には
お見通しよ。
I'm prepared for stuff like this.
カイト？
あっ？！
Kaito?
I don't... I don't ever want to see that again!
二度と…　二度と見たくない！
パズルなんて。
Puzzles should just disappear!
消えてなくなれ～～！
暴走…　逃げたか。
He's gone mad. Are you running away?
カイト！
おい　こら！　また落ちたいのか？！
Kaito!
Hey, do you want to fall again!?
でも　早く　カイトの所へ！
しかたねえ。　とっとと　クリアだ！
But we have to hurry back to Kaito!
Then we have to clear this first!
よ～し！　解けたぞ！
Okay, it's solved!
あっ　カイト！
（パネルが出る音）
Kaito!
Why won't it open?
おい　なんで開かねえんだよ！
大丈夫？　カイト！
パズルなんて…　パズルなんて→
Are you all right, Kaito?
Damn puzzles... Damn puzzles, they should all just die!
無くなっちゃえばいいんだ！
The hell's wrong with him?
…ったく　どうなってんだぁ。
って　何　抱きついてんだ　てめえ！
And why are you clinging to her?!
I'm sorry, Mom, Dad... It was my fault.
ごめんね　父さん　母さん…
僕のせいで。
このパズル…。
うわ～っ！
This puzzle...
もしかしたら　カイトの両親が
亡くなった事と関係があるのかも。
...has something to do with how his parents died?
What should we do?
どうすれば…。
≫（キュービック）ショックを
強いショックを与えて！
Shock him! Give him a strong shock!
You guys?!
≪てめえら！
いいから早く！
Do it now!
でも　そんなの　どうすれば？
But what should I do?
あっ！
ショックは無理だけど　このクッキーで。
It's not much of a shock, but these cookies...
それだよ！　ノノハスイーツ。
それなら　強いショックになる！
That's it! The Nonoha sweets!
Those are quite the strong shock!
えっ　じゃなくて　おいしいクッキーで。
貸せ！
えっ？！
You mean, they're really delicious cookies!
Give 'em here!
ほら！　ノノハスイーツだ。
Here, Nonoha sweets for you!
うっ　うっ。
ほれ！
Eat!
How are they, Kaito? Do you like them?
どう　カイト　おいしい？
ガァ！　あ～！
ひ　人殺し。
元に戻った！
Murderer!
He's back to normal.
マジで　トラウマ。
These were traumatic...?
You're horrible!
ひっど～い！
俺は　うまいと思うぜ！　ノノハ。
I think they're good, Nonoha.
おいしかったでしょう？！　ねぇ！
Say they're good, do it!
Hey, tell me they're good!
ちょっと…　おいしかって言え！
聞いてねぇ。
She's not listening.
（ビショップ）「残念ながら　大門カイト様が
倒れられた以上　話し合いは→
Sadly, due to Daimon Kaito collapsing, it has been decided that he is not fit for discussion;
不可能と判断いたしました。
よって　本日の会談は→
therefore, we are canceling today's audition.
中止とさせていただきます」。
なにっ？！
What?!
（ビショップ）「皆さん　学園まで
お送りいたします。→
I shall return you to the academy. This way, please.
どうぞ　こちらへ」。
おっ　ありがたいね！
帰りは楽ちんだ。
At least our trip back will be quick and easy!
（キュービック）まあ　しかたないね。
We didn't have a choice.
…つ～か　どうやって　ここまで
来たんだよ？　てめえらは。
By the way, how did you get here to begin with?
これ　これ。
あっ　俺のバイク？！
This.
My bike?!
おかげで間に合ったよ。
あっ？！
Thanks to that, we made it in time.
大丈夫？
ああ。
Are you all right?
Yeah.
何だったんだ？　あいつら。
何をしようとしてたんだ？
What was that about? What did they want?
（ギャモン）情けねえなあ！　タイガー＆ホース
ほじくり返されたくらいでよ。
You're pathetic! You had to pull an Ikari Shinji on us!
てめえのせいで
せっかくのチャンスが　全部ご破算だ。
We lost this great chance because of you!
Gammon!
ギャモン君！
てめえの都合なんて！
Who cares about what you want!?
カイト君　この知恵の輪　外してみて。
（ギャモン）あ～っ？！
Kaito!
Try solving this key chain's puzzle.
何なんだよ　まったく。
Leave me alone, seriously.
どうなってんだ？！　この程度のパズル
３秒もあれば　解けるはずなのに。
What's going on? I should be able to solve a puzzle like this in like three seconds.
解けねぇ。
I can't solve it.
うっ…。
カイト…　どうしたの？
Kaito, what's wrong?
学園長の悪い予感が当たったか。
So the principal's forebodings were right?
脳が　パズルに
拒否反応を起こしているんだ。
Your brain is rejecting puzzles.
このままだと　一生
パズルを解けなくなるよ。
Like this, you won't be able to solve any puzzles for the rest of your life.
はっ？！　俺が…　パズルを？！
心の声
I can't solve puzzles?!
（ルーク）倫理　常識　感情。
Ethics. Common sense. Emotions.
すべてを超越しなければ
ファイ・ブレインになることはできない。
You can't reach the Phi Brain unless you surpass all these.
「神のパズル」に挑むことも。
Let alone challenge the Divine Puzzle.
tsukue no ue de umareta sekai
This world born on my table.
ichiban saki ni kimi ni misetakatta
I wanted you to see it first.
karappo no heya sotto nukedashite hashiri hajimeteta
I sneaked out of the empty room and started to run.
iki hazamasete oka wo noboru to
As I got to the top of the hill, out of breath,
kimi ga saki ni tsuite matteita ne
you were already there waiting for me.
takusan no hajimete kimi to mitsuketa takaramono datta
It was the first of many treasures we would find together.
kanashisa de afureta toki wa
When sorrow was overflowing in me,
nanimo iwazu ni tada soba ni ite kureta ne
you just silently stayed by my side.
ima de mo wasurenai yo
I still haven't forgotten that.
mata aou ne yakusoku wo shiyou
Let's promise we'll meet again.
kie wa shinai ano hi no sayonara
The goodbye of that day we'll never forget.
boku no subete kimi ga kureta michi
All I have I got from you,
zutto kokoro no naka hikaru yo
and it will all shine in my heart forever.